原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
就这样  送上去
That's it. Get it right to the top.
稳住  慢慢来
Steady. Steady.
上去了
Up she goes.
喂  使把子力气
Hey, come on. Put your back into it, huh?
给  小子
Here you are, son.
-先生们  你们先  -右边
- Oh, gentlemen, please. - To my right.
你们  快快  动起来
And you lot, come on. Come on, get it moving.
快快
Come on, come on.
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
第六季 第七集
权力的游戏
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：Silmar 草草 潇湘月影
■
我一辈子也没见过有人能这样抡斧子
In all my days I've never seen a man swing an ax like that.
翻译：欧沈娜 盐湖凉开水 泰斯
多少人才砍倒的你
How many men did it take to cut you down?
校对：泰斯·雪诺 Silmar   顾问：屈畅(ccxx)
就一个
Just one.
时间轴：崽猪 aaaBao 加森 Avis
那他肯定壮得像头畜生
He must have been some kind of monster.
是个娘们
He was a woman.
后期：吉吉·波顿  总监：泰斯·雪诺
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
我想部分人有点怕你
I think some of the men are a bit afraid of you.
我习惯了
I'm used to it.
当初发现你的时候  我还以为你死掉几天了
When I found you, I thought you'd been dead for days.
你当时臭气熏天
The way you were stinking already
满身都是虫子
and you had bugs all over you
骨头都从这里穿出来了
and bone was coming through right there.
正打算好好埋了你  你咳嗽了一声
I was gonna give you a proper burial and then you coughed.
我差点儿拉在裤子里
Oh, nearly shit myself.
我把你弄上马车时又以为你要死了
I reckoned you were gonna die by the time I loaded you on the wagon,
可你没死
but you didn't.
那几天里我有几十次以为你要死了
Now, I reckoned you'd die a dozen more times over the next few days,
可你都没死  你靠什么撑下来的
but you didn't. What kept you going?
仇恨
Hate.
不  你还活着一定有其缘由
No, there's a reason you're still here.
可不是有吗  老子命硬就是弄不死
Aye, there's a reason. I'm a big fucker and I'm tough to kill.
不  是缘由
No, a reason.
诸神对你还有安排
Gods aren't done with you yet.
这话我从前听过
I've heard that before.
不过那家伙当时说的是别的神
Man was talking about a different god, though.
或许他说对了
Well, maybe he was right.
我对诸神也不是很了解
I don't know much about the gods.
你可入错行了
You're in the wrong line of work.
有不少自命虔诚的龟儿子
Oh, there's plenty of pious sons of bitches
以为自己懂得神或者诸神的旨意
who think they know the word of god or gods.
我就不懂  我连真神叫什么都不知道
I don't. I don't even know their real names.
也许是七神  也许是旧神
Maybe it is the Seven. Or maybe it's the old gods.
也许是光之王
Or maybe it's the Lord of Light.
又或许他们全是一个玩意儿
Or maybe they're all the same fucking thing.
我不知道
I don't know.
我相信  真正重要的
What matters, I believe,
是有一种高于我们的存在
is that there's something greater than us.
甭管它是什么  它对桑铎·克里冈自有安排
And whatever it is, it's got plans for Sandor Clegane.
你又不知道当年的我
You didn't know me back in my time.
不知道我做过什么
You don't know the things I've done.
我听过传闻
I've heard stories.
如果诸神真的存在
If the gods are real...
为什么还不惩罚我
why haven't they punished me?
他们已经惩罚你了
They have.
陛下
Your Grace.
今天读什么
What are we reading today?
《圣母之书》  主教大人
The Book of the Mother, Your Holiness.
第三章  第十二节
Chapter three, verse 12.
"如同石在水中
"As water rounds the stones, smoothing--"
磨平棱角  妇人的爱
"Smoothing what was jagged, so does a woman's love
能安抚男人的残忍天性
calm a man's brute nature.
妻子为丈夫的伤口敷药
A wife salves her husband's wounds,
母亲唱歌送儿子入梦"
a mother sings her son to sleep."
你学得很快
You learn quickly.
有些人熟读宗教经典
There are some who know every verse of the sacred text,
血液中却无一丝圣母的慈悲
but don't have a drop of the Mother's mercy in their blood
也有大字不识的粗人
and savages who can't read at all
却懂得天父的智慧
who understand the Father's wisdom.
多年来我装作关爱穷苦人  染病的人
For years I pretended to love the poor, the afflicted.
我可怜他们  却从没爱过他们
I had pity for them, but I never loved them.
他们令我厌恶
They disgusted me.
要爱他们很难
They are hard to love.
穷人令我们厌恶  因为他们就是我们
The poor disgust us because they are us,
剥去光鲜外表的我们
shorn of our illusions.
他们让我们知道  没有锦衣华服的自己是什么模样
They show us what we'd look like without our fine clothes.
没有香水的自己是什么味道
How'd we smell without perfume.
能问您一件私事吗
Can I ask you about a personal matter?
当然
Of course.
国王提到  自从团聚之后
The king mentioned that since your reunion,
您还没有与他圆房
you haven't joined him in the marriage bed.
没有
No.
您是有责任的  陛下
You have a duty, Your Grace.
对您的丈夫和国王  对您的王国
To your husband, your king, your country,
对诸神的责任
to the gods themselves.
只是...
It's just...
那些曾经驱使我的欲望  已经消失了
the desires that once drove me no longer do.
交合不一定要有欲望
Congress does not require desire
对妇人而言  耐心就足够了
on the woman's part, only patience.
我们的善业要继续下去
The king must have an heir
国王必须有继承人
if we are to continue our good work.
请您原谅
Forgive me.
有时通向真理的道路难以找寻
Sometimes the true path is hard to find.
找到它难
Hard to find
坚持走下去更难
and harder still to walk upon.
但您已经有了很大的进步
But you've made great progress.
我祈祷您的祖母能跟上您的脚步
I only pray your grandmother follows your lead.
我祖母
My grandmother?
是的
Yes.
荆棘女王是个了不起的女人
The Queen of Thorns is a remarkable woman,
一个坚强的女人
a strong woman,
也是一个执迷不悟的罪人
and an unrepentant sinner.
您要带她走上新的道路
You must teach her the new way
正如她当初教你
as she taught you the old.
否则我担心她的安危
Or I fear for her safety,
身体和灵魂
body and soul.
这货会动会说话吗
Does it move or talk?
我要跟你单独说话
I want to speak with you alone.
乌尼亚修女是我的好友  给我谏言
Septa Unella has been my true friend and counselor.
真是疯了
Oh, this is madness!
这儿不是你的圣殿  亲爱的
You're not in your sanctuary now, my dear.
我只需要吹个口哨
All I have to do is whistle
我的人就会进来  打得你头破血流
and my men will stroll in here and bash you about...
-祖母  -直到我叫他们停手
- Grandmother. - ...until I tell them to stop.
如果我会叫他们停手的话
If I tell them to stop.
-你需要好好挨顿打  -祖母  别这样
- You could use a good bashing. - Grandmother, please.
他们把你怎么了
What have they done to you?
您出兵针对大麻雀
You marched against the High Sparrow,
-攻击教会  -那是为了你
- against the Faith. - We marched for you.
诸神本会惩罚您和父亲  但他们没有
The gods could have punished you and Father, but they didn't.
-他们宽恕了你们  -那你哥哥呢
- They showed mercy. - And what about your brother?
他们对他仁慈了吗
What mercy did they show him?
洛拉斯必须供认并忏悔罪行
Loras's only hope is to confess his crimes and repent.
那样  教会便会允许他回高庭
If he does, the Faith will allow him to return to Highgarden.
他得放弃自己的头衔和继承权
He'll have to renounce his name and title...
-你疯了吗  -作为忏悔者度过终生
- Have you lost your mind? - ...and live his life as a penitent.
他是高庭的继承人  是提利尔家族的未来
He is the heir to Highgarden, the future of House Tyrell.
他可以重新开始
He can begin again.
做一个无脑狂徒
As a mindless fanatic.
做一个自由人
As a free man.
你今天就启程去高庭
You will leave for Highgarden today.
没有法律规定你必须待在这里
There is no law that says you must stay here.
我是王后
I am the queen.
我有责任服侍我夫君  国王
It is my duty to serve my husband the king.
但您该走了  祖母
But you should leave, Grandmother.
你应该待在家里
Your place is at home.
我绝不会离开你的  绝不
I will never leave you. Never.
您必须走
You must.
回家吧
Go home.
在祈祷和善行中寻求安慰
Find comfort in prayer and good works.
圣母会照看我们每个人
The Mother watches over us all.
再见了  亲爱的
I'll see you soon, my dear.
七神保佑您  祖母
Seven blessings to you, Grandmother.
我们祈祷吧
Shall we pray?
乌鸦大王  我们说过等时机到来
We said we'd fight with you, King Crow,
会跟你并肩作战  那是真心话
when the time comes and we meant it,
但我们说好的可不是这个
but this isn't what we agreed to.
他们不是异鬼
These aren't white walkers.
不是死人军团
This isn't an army of the dead.
这场仗与我们无关
This isn't our fight.
如果不是他  我们就不会站在这里
If it weren't for him, none of us would be here.
你们都会成为夜王军队的刀下鬼
All of you would be meat in the Night King's army.
我会像曼斯那样成为一堆焦骨
And I'd be a pile of charred bones just like Mance.
记得曼斯的营地吗
Remember Mance's camp?
浩浩荡荡  一眼望不到尽头
It stretched all the way to the horizon.
再看看我们现在的样子
And look at us now.
看看我们还剩下什么
Look what's left of us.
如果再失去这些人  我们就没了
And if we lose this, we're gone.
几十个部落  数百代人
Dozens of tribes, hundreds of generations.
我们会消失得无影无踪
Be like we were never there at all.
我们将是最后一代自由民
We'll be the last of the free folk.
如果我们输了的确是会如此
That's what'll happen to you if we lose.
波顿家族  卡史塔克家族  安柏家族
The Boltons, the Karstarks, the Umbers,
他们知道你们来了
they know you're here.
他们知道你们超过半数是妇孺
They know that more than half of you are women and children.
等他们干掉了我  就会冲你们来
After they finish with me, they'll come for you.
你说得对
You're right.
这场仗与你们无关
This isn't your fight.
你们不必跟我去临冬城
You shouldn't have to come to Winterfell with me.
我也不该来找你们
I shouldn't be asking you.
这跟我们说好的不一样
It's not the deal we made.
但想打败他们  我就需要你们
I need you with me if we're going to beat them,
而你们想生存下去  我们就得打败他们
and we need to beat them if you're going to survive.
乌鸦杀了他  就因为他为自由民说话
The crows killed him because he spoke for the free folk
其他南方佬都不肯
when no other southerners would.
他为我们死过
He died for us.
如果我们不愿为他牺牲  我们就是懦夫
If we are not willing to do the same for him, we're cowards.
如果我们是懦夫
And if that's what we are,
那我们活该成为最后的自由民
we deserve to be the last of the free folk.
雪诺
Snow.
你确定他们会来吗
Are you sure they'll come?
我们不像你们南方佬那么聪明
We're not clever like you southerners.
我们说到  就会做到
When we say we'll do something, we do it.
听说你要离开君临城了
I heard you were leaving King's Landing.
这与你无关
That is hardly your concern.
你孙子还被人囚禁
Your grandson is still a prisoner.
你要丢下他在牢里发霉吗
You'll leave him rotting in a cell?
洛拉斯在牢里是因为你
Loras rots in a cell because of you.
大麻雀能统治这座城市是因为你
The High Sparrow rules this city because of you.
我们两个古老的家族面临毁灭  也是因为你
Our two ancient houses face collapse because of you
因为你的愚蠢
and your stupidity.
你说得对
You're right.
我犯了大错
I made a terrible mistake.
我每天都背负着它
I carry it with me every single day.
很好
Good.
我把一支狂徒大军招进家门
I delivered an army of fanatics onto our doorstep.
现在  我们得合力对抗他们
And now we must fight them together.
我们需要彼此
We need each other.
不知道你是不是我见过的最坏的人
I wonder if you're the worst person I've ever met.
人老了  记不太清了
At a certain age, it's hard to recall.
但真正的邪恶经得起时间的考验
But the truly vile do stand out through the years.
我孙子孙女被拖进牢房时
Do you remember the way you smirked at me
你冲我得意地笑
when my grandson and granddaughter
还记得吗
were dragged off to their cells?
我记得  我永远忘不了
I do. I'll never forget it.
你爱你的孙女
You love your granddaughter.
我爱我的儿子
I love my son.
那是我唯一所知的真相
It's the only truth I know.
我们必须保护他们
We must defend them.
我要尽快离开这座可恶的城市
I'm leaving this wretched city as fast as I can
免得那个不穿鞋的狂徒把我也丢进牢房
before that shoeless zealot throws me into one of his cells.
如果你有自以为的一半聪明
If you're half as bright as you think you are,
你也会想办法离开
you'll find a way out of here, too.
决不
Never.
我决不会离开我的儿子
I'll never leave my son.
那你打算怎么办
What'll you do, then?
你孤立无援  什么也没有
You have no support. Not anymore.
你弟弟走了  大麻雀把他遣走了
Your brother's gone. The High Sparrow saw to that.
你家族的其他人抛弃了你
The rest of your family have abandoned you.
人民鄙视你
The people despise you.
你的周围都是敌人  成千上万
You're surrounded by enemies, thousands of them.
你要凭一己之力把他们全杀了吗
You're going to kill them all by yourself?
你输了  瑟曦
You've lost, Cersei.
这是我在这场悲剧中找到的唯一乐趣
It's the only joy I can find in all this misery.
快点
Pick the pace up.
别停下
Keep going.
继续走
Keep it moving!
这围城可真不怎么样
Now, that is a sorry attempt at a siege.
得有人去教教那些可悲的白痴怎么挖战壕
Someone needs to teach those sad twats how to dig trenches.
确实得有人去教
Someone certainly does.
不  我不去
Oh, no. Not me.
我只是个得势的雇佣兵
I'm just an upjumped sellsword.
你是受封的骑士  两者天差地别
You're an anointed knight. There's quite a difference.
是啊  骑士干活没钱赚
Aye, knights don't get paid.
你的直觉比兰尼斯特军中的
You have better instincts than any officer
任何将官都要敏锐
in the Lannister army.
这话就像是说我的老二
That's like saying I have a bigger cock
比无垢者军中的任何一人都大
than anyone in the Unsullied army.
估计不久后兰尼斯特的军队都将归我统帅
I expect to command all the Lannister forces before long.
你可以做我失去的右手
You can be the right hand I lost.
你曾许诺封我为贵族  赏赐我城堡
You promised me a lordship and a castle
还能娶个名门闺秀当老婆
and a highborn beauty for a wife.
这三样你都会有的  兰尼斯特有...
And you'll get all three. A Lannister always--
别说了  别他娘的说了
Don't say it. Don't fucking say it.
出来迎战  黑鱼
Come out and fight us, Blackfish.
艾德慕大人在我们手上
We have Lord Edmure.
弃城投降  否则我们就吊死他
Yield the castle or we'll hang him.
这是最后一次警告
This is your last warning.
弃城投降
Yield the castle.
你以为我不敢吗  老头
You think I won't do it, old man?
我把你侄女的喉咙割了一道大口子
I sliced your niece's throat from ear to ear.
当时你在哪儿  像个懦夫一样偷偷地跑了
And where were you? Running and hiding like a fucking coward.
弃城投降  否则我割了他的喉咙
Yield the castle or I cut his throat.
动手啊  割了他的喉咙
Go on, then. Cut his throat.
你叫罗索  对吧
Lothar, is it?
詹姆爵士
Ser Jaime.
我们不知道您要来
We didn't know you were coming.
因为你没做好周边的警戒
'Cause you didn't set a proper perimeter.
你放八千士兵大摇大摆闯进来
You just allowed 8,000 men to approach unchallenged.
好在我们是友军
Good thing we're friends
否则你们这会儿得拿屁股迎敌了
or we'd be fucking you in the ass right now.
给艾德慕大人洗个澡  吃点东西
Have Lord Edmure bathed and fed.
瓦德
Walder.
艾德慕是佛雷家族的俘虏
Edmure is a prisoner of House Frey.
只有傻瓜才发出这种有心无力的威胁
Only a fool makes threats he's not prepared to carry out.
假设我威胁要打你
Now let's say I threatened to hit you
除非你闭嘴  但你还是说个不停
unless you shut your mouth, but you kept talking.
-你觉得我会怎么做  -我他妈才不...
- What do you think I'd do? - I don't give a rat's--
我奉国王的命令夺回这座城堡
I'm here by the king's command to take back this castle.
给他洗个澡  吃点东西
Have him bathed and fed.
除非你想跟他一样
Unless you'd like to take his place.
抱歉  詹姆爵士
Apologies, Ser Jaime.
按他说的做
Do as he says.
现在围城战由我指挥
The siege is now under my command.
下次黑鱼上城墙查看的时候
The next time the Blackfish looks out from those ramparts,
他会看见一支军队  而不是乌合之众
he'll see an army at his gates, not whatever this is.
让你的人在周围挖战壕
Have your lads start digging perimeter trenches.
每隔一百码安置岗哨
Set pickets every hundred yards.
加快搭建攻城塔和投石机的速度
And work double-time on those siege towers and trebuchets.
那是我们的攻城塔...
Those are our siege towers--
我说了  围城战由我指挥
As I said, the siege is under my command.
如果你不乐意  就回家去
If that's not to your liking, go home.
给黑鱼传话
Get word to the Blackfish.
我要跟他谈判
I want a parley.
谈判还是决斗
A parley or a fight?
他是个老头
He's an old man.
你就一只手
You've got one hand.
我赌他胜
My money's on the old boy.
莫尔蒙小姐
Lady Mormont.
欢迎来到熊岛
Welcome to Bear Island.
我还记得你出生的时候  小姐
I remember when you were born, my lady.
你以我姑姑莱安娜的名字命名
You were named for my Aunt Lyanna.
据说她是个大美人  我相信你也会出落成美人
It was said she was a great beauty. I'm sure you will be, too.
我表示怀疑  我母亲就不是大美人
I doubt it. My mother wasn't a great beauty
什么美人都不是
or any other kind of beauty.
但她是伟大的战士
She was a great warrior, though.
她为你哥哥罗柏战死沙场
She died fighting for your brother Robb.
莱安娜小姐  我曾在黑城堡服侍你的舅舅
I served under your uncle at Castle Black, Lady Lyanna.
他也是伟大的战士  是位可敬的人
He was also a great warrior and an honorable man.
我曾担任他的事务官  实际上...
I was his steward. In fact--
不要再东拉西扯了  你们为何而来
I think we've had enough small talk. Why are you here?
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩出兵临冬城
Stannis Baratheon garrisoned at Castle Black
并战死之前  曾在黑城堡驻扎
before he marched on Winterfell and was killed.
他早先向你讨要帮手
He showed me the letter you wrote to him
你写的回信他给我看了
when he petitioned for men.
-上面说...  -我记得我写了什么
- It said-- - I remember what it said.
熊岛不承认除北境之王外的任何君主
Bear Island knows no king but the King in the North
而北境之王出自史塔克家族
whose name is Stark.
罗柏死了
Robb is gone,
但史塔克家族还在
but House Stark is not.
而且比以往任何时候都更需要你的帮助
And it needs your support now more than ever.
我陪同我妹妹前来请求莫尔蒙家族的效忠
I've come with my sister to ask for House Mormont's allegiance.
据我所知  你姓雪诺
As far as I understand, you're a Snow
而珊莎小姐嫁进了波顿家
and Lady Sansa is a Bolton.
还是兰尼斯特家
Or is she a Lannister?
我听到过不同的说法
I've heard conflicting reports.
我那么做只是为了活下去  小姐
I did what I had to do to survive, my lady.
但我是史塔克  我永远都是史塔克
But I am a Stark. I will always be a Stark.
你说了算  不管怎样
If you say so. In any case,
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
你不仅想要我效忠  还想要我麾下的兵士
you don't just want my allegiance. You want my fighting men.
不能任由拉姆斯·波顿占据临冬城  小姐
Ramsay Bolton cannot be allowed to keep Winterfell, my lady.
我们必须阻止他
It is our duty to stop him.
更别提他还俘虏了我们的弟弟瑞肯·史塔克
Even more so because he holds our brother Rickon Stark as prisoner.
手机APP搜索
人人影视字幕组
请你理解  小姐...
What you have to understand, my lady, is that--
我理解的是我必须对熊岛
I understand that I'm responsible for Bear Island
所有子民负责
and all who live here.
所以我为什么要打别人的仗
So why should I sacrifice
牺牲莫尔蒙家族的人
one more Mormont life for someone else's war?
插一句嘴  小姐
If it please, my lady,
我明白你的感受
I understand how you feel.
我不认识你  爵士
I don't know you, Ser...?
我是席渥斯家族的戴佛斯  小姐
Davos, my lady, of House Seaworth.
你无需向学士询问我的家族
You needn't ask your maester about my house.
很晚才有
It's rather new.
好吧  席渥斯家族的戴佛斯爵士
All right, Ser Davos of House Seaworth.
你如何明白我的感受
How is it you understand how I feel?
你从没想过会坐上这个位置
You never thought you'd find yourself in your position.
如此年轻  就要为那么多人的性命负责
Being responsible for so many lives at such a young age.
我也从未想过会有现在的地位
I never thought I'd be in my position.
我是捕蟹人的儿子  后来成了走私贩
I was a crabber's son, then I was a smuggler.
如今又在战争期间拜访一位
And now I find myself addressing the lady of a great house
名门望族的小姐
in time of war.
但我来的缘由在于  这并不是别人的仗
But I'm here because this isn't someone else's war.
这是我们的战争
It's our war.
继续说  戴佛斯爵士
Go on, Ser Davos.
你的舅舅  莫尔蒙总司令
Your uncle, Lord Commander Mormont,
任命此人为他的事务官
made that man his steward.
他选择琼恩为他的继任者  是因为他知道
He chose Jon to be his successor because he knew
此人有勇气做正确的事
he had the courage to do what was right,
即便这意味着牺牲性命
even if it meant giving his life.
因为杰奥·莫尔蒙和琼恩·雪诺都深知
Because Jeor Mormont and Jon Snow both understood
真正的战争并不是几个家族之间的小打小闹
that the real war isn't between a few squabbling houses.
而是活人与死人的较量
It's between the living and the dead.
别不当回事  小姐
And make no mistake, my lady,
死人即将到来
the dead are coming.
是真的吗
Is this true?
你的舅舅在先民拳峰与它们交战
Your uncle fought them at the Fist of the First Men.
我在艰难屯也与它们交过手
I fought them at Hardhome.
我们都输了
We both lost.
只要波顿占据临冬城  北境就是支离破碎的
As long as the Boltons hold Winterfell, the North is divided.
支离破碎的北境无法抵御夜王的进攻
And a divided North won't stand a chance against the Night King.
我理解你想要保护你的子民  小姐
You want to protect your people, my lady. I understand.
但你们无法置身事外
But there's no hiding from this.
我们必须奋起抵抗  而且勠力同心
We have to fight and we need to do it together.
莫尔蒙家族为史塔克家族守誓近千年
House Mormont has kept faith with House Stark for 1,000 years.
我们不会于今日背誓
We will not break faith today.
感谢你  小姐
Thank you, my lady.
你打算派出多少人手
How many fighting men can we expect?
六十二个
62.
-六十二个  -我们不是大家族
- 62? - We are not a large house,
但我们非常自信
but we're a proud one.
每个熊岛的汉子
And every man from Bear Island
都能以一当十
fights with the strength of 10 mainlanders.
如果他们能有小姐一半勇猛
If they're half as ferocious as their lady,
波顿家族就死定了
the Boltons are doomed.
弑君者
Kingslayer.
黑鱼
Blackfish.
我猜你来这里
I assume you're here
是为了履行对我侄女的誓约吧
to fulfill the vow you gave my niece.
我怎么没看到珊莎和艾莉亚
I don't see Sansa and Arya.
-她们不在我手上  -真遗憾
- I don't have them. - Pity.
你还想继续被关在这儿吗
Do you wish to resume your captivity?
那你来干什么
Then why are you here?
你知道我为何而来
You know why I'm here.
这座城堡属于佛雷家族
This castle belongs to House Frey.
你这是擅自侵占
You're trespassing.
我以托曼国王之名命令你投降  否则...
In the name of King Tommen, I order you to surrender or--
否则你杀了艾德慕吗
Or you'll kill Edmure?
我侄子反正都必死无疑
My nephew's marked for death no matter what.
吊死他得了
Hang him and be done with it.
艾德慕不会是最后一个
It won't stop with Edmure.
你是在逼我强攻城堡
You'll force me to storm the castle.
数百人将会死去
Hundreds will die.
我的数百人会死去  你那边会死数千人
Hundreds of mine. Thousands of yours.
能不能攻破城墙还要另说
If you can breach the walls.
我们会攻破城墙  杀掉你的每一个士兵
We'll breach them and kill every last one of you.
但如果你投降
But if you surrender,
我会饶过你手下的性命
I'll spare the lives of your men.
以我的荣誉起誓
On my honor.
你的荣誉
Your honor?
和背誓者谈判就跟在流沙上建房子一样不靠谱
Bargaining with oathbreakers is like building on quicksand.
战争已经结束了  爵士
The war is over, ser.
为什么要牺牲性命去打必败无疑的仗
Why sacrifice living men to a lost cause?
只要我还有一口气  这仗就还没打完
As long as I'm standing, the war is not over.
这是我的家
This is my home.
我在这座城堡里出生  也准备在这里死去
I was born in this castle and I'm ready to die in it.
所以你要么就进攻
So you can either attack
要么就试着把我们困死
or try to starve us out.
我们有足够撑两年的口粮
We have enough provisions for two years.
你有两年时间吗  弑君者
Do you have two years, Kingslayer?
看来你无意拯救你手下的性命
You clearly have no intention of saving your men's lives.
为什么和我谈判
Why did you come treat with me?
守城太无聊了
Sieges are dull.
我想亲自见见你  掂掂你的分量
And I wanted to see you in person, get the measure of you.
现在你见到了
Well, now you have.
对啊  见到了
Aye, now I have.
特别失望
I'm disappointed.
我不同意
The answer is no.
-葛洛佛大人  请听我说完  -我听够了
- Lord Glover, if you could just hear us out. - I've heard enough.
我们才从铁民手中夺回城堡
We've only just taken back this castle from the ironborn.
波顿家帮了大忙
The Boltons helped us do it.
现在你要我反抗他们吗
Now you want me to fight against them?
他们甚至会因为我跟你交谈而剥了我的皮
I could be skinned for even talking to you.
波顿家都是叛徒  卢斯·波顿...
The Boltons are traitors. Roose Bolton--
有其他北境家族发誓为你们而战吗
Have other northern houses pledged to fight for you?
莫尔蒙家族
House Mormont.
还有呢
And?
我们向曼德勒家族派出了信鸦...
We sent ravens to Houses Manderly--
我不管什么信鸦
I don't care about ravens.
你在请求我加入你的军队
You're asking me to join your army.
这支军队里还有谁
Who is fighting in this army?
大部分是野人
The bulk of the force is made up of wildlings.
看来传言是真的了
Then the rumors are true.
我以前都不敢相信
I didn't dare believe them.
我接待你是出于对你父亲的尊重
I received you out of respect for your father.
现在我请你们离开
Now I would like you to leave.
葛洛佛家族不会弃守祖居地
House Glover will not abandon its ancestral home
而与野人并肩战斗
to fight alongside wildlings.
-葛洛佛大人  -无须多言
- Lord Glover. - There's nothing else to say.
我想提醒您  葛洛佛家族
I would remind you that House Glover
曾宣誓效忠史塔克家族
is pledged to House Stark.
你们承诺过有求必应
Sworn to answer when called upon.
没错  我的家族侍奉了史塔克家族数百年
Yes, my family served House Stark for centuries.
我们曾为你父亲的死伤心落泪
We wept when we heard of your father's death.
当我的兄弟是这座城堡的主人时
When my brother was lord of this castle, he answered Robb's call
他响应了罗柏的召唤并拥其为北境之王
and hailed him King in the North.
然而当铁民袭击这座城堡时
And where was King Robb
罗柏国王去哪儿了
when the Ironborn attacked this castle?
当他们囚禁了我的妻儿
When they threw my wife and children in prison
残杀我们的臣民时  他又在哪儿
and brutalized and killed our subjects?
跟一个异邦婊子厮混
Taking up with a foreign whore.
他害死了自己  还有跟随他的人
Getting himself and those who followed him killed.
我曾效忠史塔克家族
I served House Stark once,
但是史塔克家族已亡
but House Stark is dead.
我们为什么要来这里
Why did we have to come here?
有些人想来
Some of us still like it.
至少喝杯酒吧
Have a drink at least.
我不想喝
I don't want one.
别走远了  亲爱的
Don't go far, love.
我马上来找你
I'll find you in a bit.
铁群岛上可没有那样的屁股
Nothing on the Iron Islands has an ass like that.
这些都提不起你的兴趣了吗
Doesn't interest you anymore?
抱歉  我不会再开这种玩笑了
I'm sorry. I won't joke about it.
我永远不会伤害你  弟弟
I'll never hurt you, little brother.
难道你不知道吗
Don't you know that?
你认为攸伦叔叔在追杀我们吗
You think Uncle Euron's hunting for us?
当然  我们只要活着  就是威胁
Of course he is. As long as we're alive, we're a threat.
他会找到我们的
He'll find us.
世界很大  而且我们的船很快
It's a great big world and we have fast ships.
喝酒
Drink.
我不想喝
I don't want any.
我不在乎你想不想  快喝
I don't care what you want. Drink.
喝光
Drink it all.
你是铁种  席恩  我知道你吃了几年的苦头
You're Ironborn, Theon. I know you've had some bad years.
几年的苦头
Some bad years?
但我看够了你落水狗一样畏畏缩缩的样子
But I'm tired of watching you cower like a beat dog.
快他妈的干了这杯麦酒
Drink the goddamn ale.
你听我说
Now listen to me.
我需要你
I need you.
我需要真正的席恩·葛雷乔伊
The real Theon Greyjoy,
不是这具行尸走肉
not this rat shit pretender.
你能找回真正的自己吗
Can you find him for me?
喝酒
Drink.
你逃出来了  听见了吗
You escaped. You hear me?
你离开了  而且永远不会回去
You got away and you're never going back.
我们会为你主持公道
We'll get justice for you.
如果真要公道
If I got justice,
那我应该被烧焦了挂在临冬城的城门上
my burnt body would hang over the gates of Winterfell.
那就去他的公道  我们会报仇的  喝酒
Fuck justice, then. We'll get revenge. Drink.
听我说
Listen to me.
你要是真的找不回原来的自己
If you're so broken that there's no coming back,
拿刀割了腕子
take a knife and cut your wrists.
一了百了
End it.
但如果你不想死  席恩  我需要你
But if you're staying, Theon, I need you.
我们要航行到弥林
We're gonna sail to Meereen.
我们要跟龙女王结盟
We're gonna make a pact with this Dragon Queen.
我们要把铁群岛夺回来
And we're gonna take back the Iron Islands.
你愿意跟我一起吗
Are you with me?
你真的愿意吗
Are you really with me?
好了  既然离下次靠岸还有一阵子
Now, since it's my last night ashore for a long while,
我要去操翻那个小婊子
I'm gonna go fuck the tits off this one.
史坦尼斯在去临冬城的途中曾驻扎于此
Stannis camped here on his way to Winterfell.
这是好事吗
And that's a good thing?
他是维斯特洛经验最丰富的指挥官
He was the most experienced commander in Westeros.
选择这里自有他的道理
He chose this place for a reason.
那些山是天然的屏障
Those mountains are a natural fortification.
还有一条饮马的小溪
There's a stream down there for the horses.
我们不会在此久留
We're not staying here long.
暴风雪随时会来
Another storm could hit any day.
没错  暴风雪对史坦尼斯的打击
Aye, the snows defeated Stannis
不比波顿家造成的少
as much as the Boltons did.
我们得趁着还能走  尽快赶到临冬城
We have to march on Winterfell now while we still can.
两千个野人
2,000 wildlings,
霍伍德家两百人  麦辛家一百四十三人
200 Hornwoods, 143 Mazins--
莫尔蒙家六十二人
62 Mormonts.
这跟我们预想的相差甚远
It's not what we'd hoped for.
但如果我们放聪明点  谨慎点  还是有机会的
But we still have a chance if we're careful and smart.
操他娘的
For fuck's sake.
现在他成了你最信任的顾问
So he's your most trusted advisor now?
就因为他从一个十岁小女孩手里借到六十二个人
Because he secured 62 men from a 10-year-old?
正是因为戴佛斯爵士  我现在才能站着跟你讲话
Ser Davos is the reason I'm standing here talking to you
而且他侍奉了史坦尼斯很多年
and he served Stannis for years.
那个在黑水河上大败而归
Stannis who lost the Blackwater,
杀害了亲弟弟  而且掉了脑袋的史坦尼斯吗
who murdered his own brother, who doesn't have a head?
远远不够  我们需要更多人
It's not enough. We need more men.
没时间了
There's no time.
如果我们去赛文城  我相信大人他...
If we went down to Castle Cerwyn, I know that Lord--
现在有多少人  我们就带多少人打
We fight with the army we have.
朋友  这不值得打架
Friends, this is not worth fighting over!
现在就值得
This'll be it, now.
好吧  我们不需要打架...
Right, now we don't need to be fighting--
-你他妈算老几  -别动手
- Who the fuck are you? - Hold on.
是啊  你他妈的算老几
Yeah, who the fuck are you?
珊莎·史塔克
我也当过兵
I was a soldier once.
所有的长官都认为我很勇敢
All my superiors thought I was brave.
其实不然  我当然没有临阵脱逃
I wasn't. I mean, I never ran from a fight.
只是因为我担心朋友看出我害怕
Only because I was afraid my friends would see I was afraid.
我当时就是胆小鬼
That's all I was, a coward.
我们服从命令  不管命令是什么
We followed orders no matter the orders.
烧毁村子
Burn that village.
好吧  我就是纵火犯
Fine, I'm your arsonist.
窃取农田的庄稼  好吧  我就是盗贼
Steal that farmer's crops. Good, I'm your thief.
杀死年轻人  免得他们拿武器反抗我们
Kill those young lads so they won't take up arms against us.
我就是杀人犯
I'm your murderer.
我记得一个女人冲着我尖叫
I remember once a woman screaming at us,
我们把她儿子拖出棚屋时  她骂我们野兽
calling us animals as we dragged her son from their hut.
但我们不是野兽
But we weren't animals.
野兽顺从天性
Animals are true to their nature
我们背叛天性
and we had betrayed ours.
我亲手割开男孩的喉咙
I cut that young boy's throat myself
她母亲一直尖叫
as his mother screamed
我朋友将她拉住
and my friends held her back.
那天晚上
That night...
我感觉羞愧
I felt such shame.
羞愧难当
Shame was so heavy on me,
我吃不下  我睡不着
I couldn't eat, I couldn't sleep.
我只能盯着漆黑夜空
All I could do was stare into that dark sky
听着那个母亲尖叫着儿子的名字
and listen to that mother screaming her son's name.
从那以后尖叫声一直萦绕在我脑子里
I'll hear her screaming the rest of my life.
我知道我没法让男孩活过来
Now, I know I can never bring that lad back.
我余生能做的就是
All I can do with time I've got left
为这个世界带来一点点善良
is bring a little goodness into the world.
这是我们大家都能做的  对不对
That's all any of us can do, isn't it?
停止烧杀掳掠
Never too late to stop robbing people,
开始帮助别人
to stop killing people.
任何时候都不晚
Start helping people.
任何时候回头都不晚
It's never too late to come back.
不是说等待众神回应你的祈祷
And it's not about waiting for the gods to answer your prayers.
跟神没有关系  只跟你们自己有关
It's not even about the gods. It's about you.
学会回应自己的祈祷
Learning you have to answer your prayers yourself.
七神保佑诸位  朋友们
Seven save you, friends.
我们能帮什么忙
How can we help you?
你们在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我们在谈论生活
Well, we're talking about life.
你们呢
You?
保护人
Protecting the people.
我们感谢各位的保护
Well, we thank you for your protection.
保护我们免遭什么
Who are you protecting us from?
你们有马吗
Do you have any horses?
没有马
No horses.
没有金子  没有铁器
No gold. No steel.
那就食物  保护人的活儿很容易饿肚子
Food, then. Protecting the people is hungry work.
那是当然
I'm sure it is.
欢迎你们留下来吃晚饭
You're welcome to stay for supper,
不过我们自己都在饿肚子
but we have hungry mouths here.
保重
Stay safe.
长夜黑暗  处处险恶
The night is dark and full of terrors.
"七神保佑诸位  朋友们"
"Seven save you, friends."
我就是个修士  还能说什么
I'm a fucking septon. What was I supposed to say?
他们不信你的七神
They don't believe in your Seven.
他们是兄弟会的  他们追随红神
They're from the Brotherhood. They follow the Red God.
好啊  咱们都欢迎
Aye, well, all are welcome here.
还有  我们没他们要的东西
Anyway, we got nothing for them.
当然有  你有食物
Sure, you do. You've got food,
你还有铁器  虽然你说没有
you've got steel even if you say you don't.
你还有女人
And you've got women.
你想怎么办  跟他们打吗
What do you want to do? Fight them?
杀死他们吗
Kill them?
那你只能孤军奋战
It'd be you against all of them.
这里的人们根本不会打仗
I mean, these people don't know how to fight.
你会
You do.
我不想打了
I'm done with fighting.
为了保命也不打吗
Even if it's to protect yourself?
暴力就是恶疾
Violence is a disease.
传染开去是治不好恶疾的
You don't cure a disease by spreading it to more people.
你死了也治不好恶疾
You don't cure it by dying, either.
你今天干的活够多了
You've done enough work for one day.
来吃晚饭吧
Come on up for some supper.
今晚会很冷
It's gonna be a cold night.
我们需要柴火
We'll need firewood.
我给你留一碗
I'll save you a bowl of stew.
也许还有一点藏起来的麦酒
Might even have some ale hidden away.
他不撒谎
He's not a lying man.
他说铁舰队在奴隶湾
He says the Iron Fleet's in Slaver's Bay.
我愿意相信他
I'm inclined to believe him.
我才不想靠近那些疯子
I'm not going anywhere near those mad fuckers.
你是维斯特洛人
You're Westerosi.
关你什么事
What do you care?
我想订一张回家的船票
I want to book passage home.
就你  付不起
You? Can't afford it.
你从哪里偷来的
Where'd you steal this from?
关你什么事
Why do you care?
我们两天后出发
We leave in two days.
你可以在大舱里有个吊铺
You can have a hammock in steerage.
我要一间舱房
I want a cabin.
我们天亮就出发
And we'll leave at dawn.
日出见
See you at sunrise.
小姑娘
Sweet girl.
■
人人美剧APP
看美剧就来人人美剧
更新快 无删减
最大最全的美剧平台
扫码即刻下载
Zimuzu特别推荐
■
各大应用市场均可下载